Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV. Film and Video Recordings
  - I Just Fuck Myself, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_413)
  - I Love You Amy Fisher, Undated (Box 1, U-matic 267_564, Box 9, Vhs 267_696, 267_692)
    267_564 is labeled as the master recording.
  - I've Got Fever, 1993 (Box 8, Vhs 267_734)
  - Ice Phantom, Undated (Box 4, U-matic 267_606, Box 9, Vhs 267_696)
  - Ice Phantom / Spectral Programs, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_424)
    The tape's label says "Ice Phantom 16'50 approx NR2; Spectral Programs 16' approx NR3; Master"
  - The Ideal Forms: 5 Nude Solo Dances, Undated (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_533)
  - Imperilled, Undated (Box 5, U-matic 267_624, Box 10, Vhs 267_752)
  - Improvisation at Hot House P.S. 122 - Alan Sondheim and Foofwa D'imobilite, December 6, 1998 (Box 10, Vhs 267_748)
  - Internet, May 10, 1995; Duration: Approx. 38 min (Box 7, U-matic 267_645)
  - Interruption, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_698, Box 16, Hi8 267_398)
  - Into the European Mirror, 1994; Duration: 56 min (Box 8, Vhs 267_728)
  - Island, Undated (Box 2, U-matic 267_583, Box 7, Vhs 267_667, Box 16, Hi8 267_390, Box 8, Vhs 267_716, Box 10, Betamax 267_760)
  - Japan, August, 1979; Duration: Approx. 55 min (Box 2, U-matic 267_579, 267_572)
    267_579's label says, "Duplicate, without time base correction. With Alan Sondheim, Laura Hayes. Produced at Monte-Video Hartford Connecticut, John Hyjek Camera and Tech. Produced and directed by Alan Sondheim, August 1979. Screenings at Montevideo Franklin Furnace NYC< Real Art Ways, Hartford." It also has an address to Sondheim's office at UCLA. 267_572's label says, "For Grant Application. This videotape is similar to my current films; the latter are masterprints only, and can only be rarely projected. Shown at: Museum of Modern Art, New York City; American Center, Paris; Kitchen, New York City. Distributed by: Art Metropole, Toronto, Canada."
  - Je Suis Sage by Kimberly Bartosik with Frederic Gafner, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_742)
    This tape includes versions with and without subtitles. Unclear whether the subtitles are in English or in French.
  - Jennifer, February 28, 1997 (Box 16, Hi8 267_386)
  - Jennifer, Where Are You? Leslie Thornton, 1981; Duration: 10 minutes (Box 21, Vhs 267_783)
  - Jerome (Everything), Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_745)
  - Joanna Films - 1st 3 Dailywork Transfers, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_418, Box 7, Vhs 267_656)
  - Joanne, 1993 (Box 16, Hi8 267_405)
  - Joanne - yr 300 footage, Halifax footage, Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_029, 267_030)
  - Joanne Martin / SHAVE with Ann Daly, Undated (Box 15, Hi8 267_438)
    The tape's label says "Joanne Martin 11' NR3 Needs sound boost mixed; Shave (w/ Ann Daly) 9'12" NR3 PCM"
  - Jodee Jingles, 1993 (Box 8, Vhs 267_734)
  - Jodee Material; Vulture; Ceremony (Alice); Dragonfly; Courteway (Box 15, Hi8 267_449)
    The tape's label says, "(Jodee Material 1st 10'-11' of beginning); Vulture approx 20' NR 2 Mixed; Ceremony (Alice) 6'25" NR2 Mixed; Dragonfly 14'; Courteway 9' NR3"
  - Jodi Drugs, Alan, Lori, Undated (Box 7, U-matic 267_650)
  - Jodie Questioning Me / Alice Questioning Me / Moving Dance in Studio w SFX / SFX w/ Police and Text / Sex Complex / Mark / Police / Sex image cycle / Alice reading, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_697)
  - Juan Davila, Undated (Box 7, Vhs 267_665)
  - Kabbalah, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_495)
  - Kasper Hauser in Holocaust City - Psychotic Tapes, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_400, Box 10, Betamax 267_754, Betamax 267_756)
  - Landscape, 1980 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_467, Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_549)
    267_467 is a compilation tape labeled "4 California Tapes." Its label also says, "EIAJ Black and White." 267_549 is also a compilation tape.
  - Launch, Undated (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_548)
  - Laura, 1979 (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_006, 267_009)
  - Lexicon, 1980-1981 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_477, 267_467, Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_543, 267_547, 267_550)
    267_477 is labeled as the master recording. 267_467 is a compilation tape labeled "4 California Tapes." Its label also says, "EIAJ Black and White." 267_543 is a compilation tape labeled "7 California Tapes." 267_549 and 267_550 are also compilation tapes.
  - Life (Explain), Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_390, Box 8, Vhs 267_716)
  - Life Story..., Undated (Box 15, Hi8 267_440, Box 9, Vhs 267_677)
    The tape label says, "Life Story Master, AFM Sound; 1st Scene Until WD. 'Honest'; Flash 2; Then NR3 until End; (W. Jodee) + OR PCM; MOTHER, PCM NR2 6'"
  - Liquid, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_677, Box 16, Hi8 267_405)
  - Lori Tape, Undated (Box 15, Hi8 267_459)
  - M Wilson / Alan Sondheim, Undated; cuid30329 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_506)
  - M Wilson: Rapping Video Segment, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_506)
  - Magic in the Air - Prelinger Associates, Inc., Undated (Box 6, U-matic 267_633)
    The only label on the tape seems to be an old, recycled label and may be inaccurate.
  - Margaret, 1993; Duration: 20 minutes (Box 3, U-matic 267_589, Box 6, U-matic 267_634, 267_641, Box 16, Hi8 267_414, 267_422, Box 10, Vhs 267_750)
  - Margaret Curtis / Alan Sondheim: Four videos for preview, 1990 (Box 8, Vhs 267_719)
  - Margaret Curtis: Clear White Fruit, 1990 (Box 9, Vhs 267_688)
  - Margaret Curtis: The Girding, 1990 (Box 9, Vhs 267_688)
  - Mastering Suture - Matters Pertaining to Joan of Arc, Undated (Box 3, U-matic 267_597)
    Another label says, "Nikuko Make-up Raw Footage" but it is crossed out.
  - Maximax (Work in Progress) by/with Foofwa d'Imobilité, 1997; Duration: 6 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_701)
  - Memory and 1973 and Master (Box 8, Vhs 267_722)
  - Millennium, March, 2001 (Box 14, Minidv 267_376, 267_380)
  - Mobil #7, August 2, 1992 (Box 6, U-matic 267_635)
  - Mobil Cutting Oil #7, June 22, 1991 (Box 5, U-matic 267_615)
  - Monday Afternoon Martin, 1991 (Box 16, Hi8 267_393)
  - Mother (Pieta), 1993 (Box 9, Vhs 267_677, Box 16, Hi8 267_411, Box 8, Vhs 267_734)
  - Motherstructure, 1993 (Box 8, Vhs 267_734)
  - Mud, Undated (Box 15, Hi8 267_451, Box 6, U-matic 267_641)
  - Mullen, Undated (Box 14, Minidv 267_377)
  - Murmur, 1993; Duration: 10 min (Box 16, Hi8 267_422, Box 10, Vhs 267_750)
  - music / consciousness / gender by Benjamin Boretz, 1994-1995; Duration: 89 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_703)
    This recording contains "texts, musics, textsoundmusics, images for live speaker and prerecorded speakers, musics and images on audio and videotape." It was recorded and produced by Mary Lee Roberts, 1996.
  - Narrative Master, Undated (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_479)
  - Nature of the Universe, May 31, 1992 (Box 16, Hi8 267_387, Box 8, Vhs 267_727)
    267_387 is labeled as the master recording.
  - News For Teaching, Undated (Box 8, Vhs 267_731)
  - Nexus, September 11, 1993 (Box 16, Hi8 267_404)
  - Nihon Coin Over by Frederic Gafner, 1994-1995; Duration: 25 min (Box 8, Vhs 267_705, Box 9, Vhs 267_693)
  - Nikuko, December 7, 1999 (Box 3, U-matic 267_598)
    The tape's label says, "Nikuko Master 12/7/99; Also Master 1, 12/6/99; The Experimental Television Center, Owego NY"
  - NYC FG Waterfall ACA Briarcliff Shreveport, Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_024)
  - NYSCA, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_747)
  - Old Man Canadian Swim, 1991 (Box 10, Vhs 267_770, Box 9, Vhs 267_695)
  - Old Moving Car Footage, Punk Footage, Undated (Box Films 2, 16mm film reels 267_004)
  - Old World, undated (Box 21, Vhs 267_781)
  - On the Vivid by Foofwa D'Imobilité, 1996; Duration: 29 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_700)
  - On the Way to the Lake, Undated (Box 3, U-matic 267_584, Box 7, Vhs 267_657)
    267_584 is labeled as the master recording.
  - On Your Belly, Undated (Box 1, U-matic 267_564, Box 9, Vhs 267_696)
  - One Day in the Life of Tryon, 1985 (Box Films 2, 16mm film reels 267_016)
  - One0One by Frederic Gafner, September, 1994 (Box 6, U-matic 267_632, Box 7, U-matic 267_649, Box 9, Vhs 267_690, Box 10, Vhs 267_777)
  - One0One by Frederic Gafner - Edit, 2003 (Box 7, Vhs 267_664)
  - Oscelloscope Films, 1970-1975 (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_005)
    Original can label says "1. 2 x 3 Oscelloscope Waveform; 2. Nova Scotia Gestmal [?] Work; 3. Orseus; 4. Beth Doubled; 5. wh SEM; 6. Oscelloscope over TV, Overlaw Talking Heads; 7. Oscelloscope; 8. Chris and Don; 1972? - 1973 - 1974?"
  - Outfit, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_491, 267_497, Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_512)
    267_491 is labeled as "dub." 267_497 is labeled as "Final." 267_512 is labeled as "Final dub."
  - Papago, 1977 (Box 2, U-matic 267_580)
  - Parables - ETC, 2000 (Box 14, Minidv 267_375)
    The cassette's label states that it is a duplicate.
  - Peggy and Fred in Hell (Scenes and Shots from the Series), Produced and Directed by Leslie Thornton, 1981-1991; Duration: 10 min (Box 10, Vhs 267_772, Box 8, Vhs 267_725)
  - Performance in Hellerau: Foofwa d'Imobilité, June 5, 1999 (Box 9, Vhs 267_684)
  - Piece, 1991 (Box 7, Vhs 267_665, Box 9, Vhs 267_694)
  - Planet I and II, Undated (Box 8, Vhs 267_721)
  - Postmodern Pobre / Postmodern Sureño / Mud / Miscellaneous until end of tape, 1992-1993; Duration: 1 hour 20 min (Box 8, Vhs 267_730)
  - Postmodern Sureño, 1993; Duration: Approx. 58 min (Box 9, Vhs 267_672, 267_681, Box 7, U-matic 267_654)
    The label lists Dawnja Burris as a collaborator. Other labels on 267_672 say "Internet Video," and "Jennifer (?) Tape." 267_681's label adds, "Second Work Sample Produced During Initial Trip to El Paso/Cuidad Juarez 11/92-1/93"
  - Probe (Insertion Into An Older Tape), Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_486)
  - PTG, Undated (Box 7, Vhs 267_665, Box 9, Vhs 267_694)
  - Puppet Show, 1971 (Box Quarantine 1, Half inch video reel 267_800)
  - Puppet Show / Polygons Original, October 20, 1971 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_525)
    The tape's label also says, "Aram Saroyan; 20 min; Black and White; RISD"
  - Question of Little Deaths, 1991 (Box 10, Vhs 267_770, Box 15, Hi8 267_445)
  - The Raft of the Medusa: five voices on colonies, nations and histories, 1993; Duration: 1:39:00 (Box 8, Vhs 267_736)
  - Recall, Darrin Martin and Torsten Zenas Burns, 1998; Duration: 14 min (Box 8, Vhs 267_729)
    Includes contact information for Darrin Martin
  - Recent Film Transfers (Raw Materials), 1987 (Box 10, Vhs 267_763)
    This tape includes footage later used in "The Third Millennium (The Year 3000)," and footage used for Damaged Life concerts.
  - Recent Selected, July 21, 1992 (Box 10, Vhs 267_771)
  - The Reed Point Monolog - Alan Sondheim and Laura Hayes, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_492, 267_501, Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_514, 267_517, Box 6, U-matic 267_630, Box 7, U-matic 267_651)
    267_651 is labeled as the master recording.
  - Reg 8, Undated (Box 8, Vhs 267_737)
  - Remnants (Fold Catastrophe), 1978 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_513, 267_516, 267_524)
    267_516's label also says, "Master: Please be careful! Tape runs full length of reel. EIAJ Standard."
  - Remnants from the Beginning of the Period of Destruction by Alan Sondheim with music by A.S. and Laurie Anderson, 1977 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_476, Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_493)
    267_476 is an empty case with no videotape inside; 267_493 is noted as the Master.
  - Repetition, 1972 (Box Quarantine 1, Half inch video reel 267_800)
  - Reverse, 1980 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_467)
    267_467 is a compilation tape labeled "4 California Tapes." The label also says, "EIAJ Black and White."
  - Reverse Wound at 000 Feet, Begin 728 to 880, Undated; cuid30333 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_537)
  - Rhythm Fest #12, Undated (Box 5, U-matic 267_629)
    This recording features Rhythm Fest Backstage, Girlz Nose, Lesbian Belle, and Paige.
  - Rhythm Fest - Mayday, Undated (Box 4, U-matic 267_614)
  - Ridge, Undated (Box 15, Hi8 267_450)
    The tape's label says "8 Feed - Reusable; 1 min master of Ridge (8'); ACM sound; Use w/ NR3"
  - Roam Sweet Home, a film by Ellen Spiro, 1996; Duration: 56 min (Box 10, Vhs 267_778)
  - Robin, Undated; cuid30332 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_521, 267_522)
  - Rockefeller, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_746)
  - Rough Cut Segment, 1981 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_543)
  - S.E.M. Imagery, Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_034)
  - Sample Tape, Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_779)
  - San Diego, 1981 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_543)
  - Scan, 1972 (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_498, Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_547)
    Tape 267_498's label notes that it is the original version of the recording. Tape 267_547 also includes a recording of "Wormhole Model"
  - Sections 1-8 of First Film Series - Supporting Materials for Guggenheim Application, 1981-1982; Duration: Approx. 50 min (Box 1, U-matic 267_568)
    The tape's label says, "Alan Sondheim, sections 1-8 of first film series, 1981-1982, from 16mm optical sound black and white. This series consists of 40+ segments, made at the rate of one reel per week, edited in-camera. They deal with ideology, politicization, the position of the subject, and are made to be shown together."
  - Selections: Exhibition Consideration Tape: Desperate Thought Rises to the Surface, 1991; Duration: 1 hour 50 min, From Hi8 PCM Stereo (Box 8, Vhs 267_741)
  - Sequestered Geography Section (Texas), Undated (Box 5, U-matic 267_627)
  - Sexual Tape With Burglar Alarm, Undated (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_552)
  - Sexualities, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_419, Box 9, Vhs 267_686)
    According to the label of videotape 267_686, the recordings included in Sexualities emph> are "My Cunt" 1, 2, and 3, "BADBOYBADGIRL," "Milking," "Flesh and Bone," "I Want This Hole," "Body Burns," "Borders," "Arise," "Sorrow Cock," "Cunt," "Masturbate," and "Radiate."
  - She Came In and Out of Me - Film the End, 1987 (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_018)
  - Short Road Bit, Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_036)
  - Skinny Was Dead, August, 1992 (Box 7, U-matic 267_652)
  - Slab, 1981 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_542, 267_543, 267_549, 267_550)
    267_542 is an empty reel - no videotape present. 267_543 is a compilation tape labeled "7 California Tapes." 267_549 and 267_550 are also compilation tapes.
  - Slate, 1980 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_467)
  - Snow / Dog / Acker Tape, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_428)
    The tape's label says "Snow: Use NR3 digital; Break in control between Snow and Dog."
  - The Society of the Spectacle by Guy Debord (an Ediciones la Calavera Project), Undated (Box 10, Vhs 267_764)
  - Some Fall Shots, Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_035)
  - Someone Dies, October 22, 1993 (Box 14, Hi8 267_383)
  - Souvenir, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_412)
    The tape's label says "Souvenir; Feedback [illegible] use with mixed audio; Masters"
  - Special Glasses, July, 1993 (Box 16, Hi8 267_405)
    The tape's label says "1. Liquid - Unusable 7', Usable AFMvPCM NR3 7'; Clara 14' AFMvPCM NR2 Both Mastered Thru 3/4"; 3. Joanna 11' NR2 PCM, louder; Special Glasses, 23' Mixed NR 0-2."
  - Stars Come Out, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_413, Box 9, Vhs 267_698)
  - Stealing Time (Two Versions) / Collected Works / Steam, Undated (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_472)
  - Strange Space by Leslie Thornton and Ron Vawter, 1992 (Box 8, Vhs 267_732)
    A note on the cover says, "Missing head and tail credits."
  - Stub, 1981 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_543)
  - Structural Film, 1972; cuid30318 (Box 24, 8mm film reel 267_142)
  - Talking Cure, 1982 (Box 15, 16mm film reels 267_013)
  - Tasmanian Master, 1983 (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_014)
  - Terpsicorp and Marlabor by Foofwa d'Imobilité, September, 1999; Duration: 32 min; color (Box 8, Vhs 267_726, 267_715, Box 9, Vhs 267_676, 267_689, Box 10, Vhs 267_743)
    267_676 is labeled as the "original three performances." 267_689 is labeled as "quickcam shots." 267_743 is labeled as "rough cuts."
  - Paris Performance - Foofwa d'Imobilité, February, 1999 (Box 9, Vhs 267_673)
  - Terror, December, 1993 (Box 16, Hi8 267_420, Box 4, U-matic 267_609, Box 9, Vhs 267_704)
  - Testmaster, Undated (Box 1, U-matic 267_565)
  - These Smooth Lines Comfort Me, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_698)
  - Theses After Marx / Red Art Brigade Whitney Show, 1976; cuid21361 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_510, 267_522, 267_526, 267_527, Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_475)
    267_526 is labeled as "dub."
  - This Is the Film in Which You Are Forgiven and This Is the Film in Which I Am Lost, 1982-1984 (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_015)
    Original film can label says "Pia -- This is the film in which you are forgiven; This is the film in which I am lost; Silent 16-18 fps; 1982-1983; Alan Sondheim"
  - This Really Is Trying to Tell You Something, 1980 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_544)
    267_544 is a compilation tape labeled as "3 California Tapes."
  - Thornton / Greet / Imobilité, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_680)
    titles are illegible
  - Titles ETC Master, 1997 (Box 16, Hi8 267_403)
    The tape label says "1. And Then This Happened; 2. Alan S. 1997 Thanks to ETC/FUA; 3. I Bridge My Love From Here To You Clara; 4. Yes, IX! I do love Amy Fisher, perhaps you've heard of Clare? (I40)."
  - Titling From Tape # 6, 11, 4, 9, 10, undated (Box 21, Vhs 267_786)
  - Track, 1970-1980 (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_530, Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_467, Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_550)
    267_530 is labeled as the master recording. 267_467 is a compilation tape labeled "4 California Tapes." Its label also says, "EIAJ Black and White." 267_550 is also a compilation tape.
  - Trance Films, 1991 (Box 7, Vhs 267_665, Box 10, Betamax 267_756, Box 9, Vhs 267_694)
  - Transfer Original, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_507)
  - Travel Footage - Southwest and Northeast U.S., 1975-1981 (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_008)
    Original reel label says: "0. Introduction 1981; 1. Caldera, Los Alamos; 2. Pueblo ruin / Atomic Museum; 3. UCLA / Santa Monica; 4. NYC / Staten Island Market View; 5. Far Hills, N.J. '75; 6. S.E.M., Nova Scotia 77? 7. Instrumenalists, '81?"
  - Traveller Film / Arctic Tapes, circa 1985; cuid30317 (Box 24, Super 8mm film reel 267_143)
  - Tre Interview, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_679)
  - Trials / Vincent / John / Foof / Animal / Organix, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_674)
  - Trilby by Alan Sondheim and Azure Carter, 2002 (Box 10, Vhs 267_744, Box 8, Vhs 267_711)
  - Tyler Stallings, 1. Inside to the Outside, 2. Hospital Thoughts, 3. Bleed, 4. Virusmachine, 5. Stale, 6. How I Colonized Myself, 1989; Duration: 1. Inside to the Outside, 4:24; 2. Hospital Thoughts, 6:49; 3. Bleed, 4:30; 4. Virusmachine, no duration notated; 5. Stale, 1:36; 6. How I Colonized Myself, 14:37. (Box 21, Vhs 267_784)
  - Untitled, 1980 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_478, 267_481, 267_483, Box Quarantine 1, Half inch video reel 267_801)
  - Untitled Film, 1985 (Box Films 2, 16mm film reels 267_031)
  - Upstairs / Tryon Tape, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_682)
  - Vienna, Undated (Box 5, U-matic 267_628, Box 16, Hi8 267_415, Box 8, Vhs 267_721)
    Other labels say "Work Visuals #2" and "Mendieta Photo Stills."
  - Virgin Mary, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_413, Box 9, Vhs 267_698)
  - Vladivostok, 1977 (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_487, Box Quarantine 1, Half inch video reel 267_797)
    267_797 is labeled as Tape I. 267_487 is labeled as Tape II.
  - Vulture Until End, Undated (Box 7, Vhs 267_665)
  - Watchman Park / Frank and the Ladies / 5 Minews / Aplets Mister, Undated; Duration: Watchman Park, 09:19, Frank and the Ladies, 07:32, 5 Minews, 13:04, Aplets Mister, 25:22; a note says "Miller" (Box 8, Vhs 267_714)
  - Waveform Pulse, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_470, 267_484)
    The tape's label also says, "1. Wimhurst; 2. I Am Metaphysics; 3. Oscilloscope Voice; 4. "I Am Metaphysics"; 5. Feedback; 7; Pulse"
  - Way Out West, Undated (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_026)
  - Wimhurst Generator Tape, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_496)
    The tape's label also says "Static Machine / Pulse Into Echo / Performance"
  - Without / Compilation Reel 3, 1972 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_538)
    The tape's label says, "1. Beth Cannon, 1972; 2. Light Mallet John Woodson 5 min, 1972; 3. John Woodson / Karin Achenbach, 1972, Information transfer; 4. Polygon 10 min, 1972; Without - 1st 6-7 minutes; Monitor image should be very dark and high contrast so that only white paint is visible - play in dark room. Fast forward to 161-839 in reverse."
  - Woman's Tape, Undated (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_500)
  - Work of Inferno [Illegible], Undated (Box Films 1, 8mm film reel 267_023)
  - Works From Miami, Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_675, Box 10, Vhs 267_749)
  - World War II Canadian Training Film, Undated (Box Films 2, 16mm film reels 267_022)
  - Wormhole Model, 1971 (Box 19, Half inch video reel 267_474, Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_547)
    Tape 267_474 is labeled as the original recording. Tape 267_547 also includes a recording of "Scan."
  - Wupatki, 1990 (Box 9, Vhs 267_688)
  - TR FAV, Undated; cuid30321 (Box 24, 8mm film reel 267_138)
  - You, Undated (Box 8, Vhs 267_721)
  - You Wouldn't Believe, Undated (Box 16, Hi8 267_413, Box 9, Vhs 267_698)
  - Young Deconstructor (Box 15, Hi8 267_444,, Box 16, Hi8 267_410)
    267_444's label says "Master / Color / Bridge (No One Listens)"
  - [Illegible Title], Undated (Box 9, Vhs 267_687)
  - [No Title], undated (Box 21, Vhs 267_659)
- Series V. Academic Career and Events
  - Toronto / UCLA, August, 1966; cuid30319 (Box 24, 8mm film reel 267_142)
  - Intellectual Interview Determining the Statement and Consistency of Jesis Christ - 3 Interviews, RISD, March, 1971 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_302)
  - 4-3-2-0 Spacing at Brown University / Conversation / Space Stream, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Half inch video reel 267_546)
    The tape's label says, "1. 4320 Brown University Meta-4 Computer; Charles Strauss Programmer 1971; Andrea Kovass / Beth Cannon; Conversation - John Woodson / Alan Sondheim; Four Overlays, 1972; Space Stream Marge Anderson, 1971; College Blog R.I.S.D."
  - Halifax NSCAD, 1972 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_273)
  - "Quinn on Quine" Faculty Systems Group, November 20, 1972 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_267, Box 12, Audiocassette 267_256, 267_262)
  - 4-3-2-0 Spacing: Brown University, 1973; cuid21360 (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_482)
  - Crystal Pond / Air Gallery - Rosemary, May, 1973; EIAJ standard (Box 17, Half inch video reel 267_528, Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_490)
  - Alan Sondheim at USCD, May 23, 1974 (Box 12, Audiocassette 267_210, Box 14, Audiocassette 267_364)
  - Alan Sondheim Profile by Kil Schwartz [Illegible] NYC, October 8, 1975 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_324)
  - "Blank Tape" - Museum of Modern Art Showing, October, 1976 (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_494)
  - VIDEO / TAPE: Tape prepared for talk at Ontario Gallery of Art, February 2, 1978; cuid30330 (Box 20, Half inch video reel 267_518)
  - Quebec Country Western Reading, July 10, 1980 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_285)
  - Pre Convention I and II, August 6, 1981 (Box 13, Audiocassette 267_194)
  - Israel Bond Event - Presentation to Evelyn Sondheim by Judge Max Roseun, Response by Evelyn Sondheim, November 22, 1981 (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_279)
  - American Indian Pow-Wow - Grand Prairie, Texas, September 7, 1986 (Box 25, Quarter inch audio reel 267_135)
  - Nexus Exhibition, Includes Opening - Atlanta, January 11, 1991 (Box 14, Hi8 267_382)
  - Exhibition Master: Rainbow @21, Millenium 1994 (Box 8, Vhs 267_739)
  - Brown University MCM 170 Class, c. 2007 (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_040)
  - Brown University Intro Film, c. 2007 (Box Films 1, 16mm film reels 267_041)
  - Cal Arts, Undated (Box 11, Audiocassette 267_271, 267_298)